Finding Aid for Residential College (University of Michigan) records, 1957-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Social Science Program, 1976-1991
  - Student-Faculty Research Community
    - Reports
      - "Collective work in small alternative enterprises,", 1978 (Box 4)
      - "Conflict and Power on the Campus: Studies in the Political Economy of the University of Michigan,", 1978 (Box 4)
      - "A look at the other side of the tracks, the river and the highway: Social and Political Organization in Two Ann Arbor Neighborhoods: A Comparative Study" [Northside and Bryant neighborhoods], 1978 (Box 5)
      - "A History of Jackson Prison, 1920-1975", 1979 (Box 5)
      - "Juggling Contradictions: Women's Ideas About Families,", 1979 (Box 5)
      - "Creating Local Resources from Sun, Wind, and Earth: Individual Experiences in Self-reliance Washtenaw County, Michigan,", 1981 (Box 5)
      - "Adult Learning in Informal Settings: Thirty Adults View Their Experiences,", 1981 (Box 5)
      - "The Transformation of Michigan Politics in the 1940s", 1985 (Box 5)
      - "Down Home Up North: Appalachian Images of Migration and Place in the Hills and in Detroit,", 1985 (Box 5)
      - "Exploring Political Activism: A Quantitative and Qualitative Study of Two Neighborhoods and Two Dozen Activists in Southeastern Michigan,", 1987 (Box 5)
      - "Enrollment and Retention of Black Students: Four Case Studies,", 1990 (Box 5)
      - "Black Enrollment and the Mackenzie High School Visit, 1990" (Box 5)
      - "An Analysis of the Results of Recruitment Efforts Related to the Detroit Public Schools/University of Michigan Collaborative Project,", 1991 (Box 5)
    - Workshops-Interviewing, 1970-1985 (Box 20)
    - Workshops-Nature of Research, 1979-1985 (Box 20)
    - Workshops-Skills, 1984-1987 (Box 20)
- Photographs, 1964; 1967; 1970-1972
  The Photographs series (0.2 linear feet, 1964-1994) consists of several folders of photographs, the first containing copies of photos of RC freshman field trips to Kentucky in 1970-1972, and the second, a photo of the Residential College Faculty Planning Committee from 1967 along with an undated photograph. It also includes a folder containing copies of photos of a 1964 Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) protest at Detroit's AAA office. The provenance of the photos is unknown. Other folders include photos of faculty-student committee meetings, probably from the late 1960s, photos from the 1994 orientation, and photos of faculty members, students, social events, and East Quad. This series also contains color slides of faculty, students, and several classes, including drama, curtain design, and sculpture. Digital content (7.5 GB) includes 18 .ZIP files containing several thousand .JPG image files on subjects such as the college's 40th anniversary celebration in 2007, theatrical performances, faculty members, art gallery and studios, and Keene Theater grand opening gala. Topical Files series contains photographs from a 1983 field trip to Pioneer Valley in Massachusetts
  - 40th Anniversary, 2007; .ZIP file
  - Advisory Council (RCAC), circa, 2003; .ZIP file
  - Appalachian Field Trips, 1970-1972
  - Art Gallery, 2002-2003; .ZIP file
  - Art Studios, 2006; .ZIP file
  - Benefit and Outdoor Theater Performance, 2004; .ZIP file
  - Residential College Faculty Planning Committee and unidentified, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Detroit CORE Chapter Protest at AAA, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Faculty-Student Committee Meeting, circa late, 1960s (Box 20)
  - French Play, circa, 2003; .ZIP file
  - Graduation, 2004; .ZIP file
  - Keene Theater Grand Opening Gala, 2009; .ZIP file
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976; 2002-2007; .ZIP file
    (Includes photos of 40th anniversary, East Quad, performances, art gallery, faculty, students in class, a visit by LS&A Dean Terry McDonald, and parents weekend)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1994; undated (Box 20)
  - Orientation, 1994 (Box 20)
  - RC People (Mostly Faculty), 1967-2004; .ZIP file
  - Semi-Formal, circa, 2003; .ZIP file
  - Senior Dinner, 2003; .ZIP file
  - Slides, 1972-1978 (Box 20)
  - Telling It Program, circa, 2003; .ZIP file
  - Website Photos, 2007; .ZIP file
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series (13.5 linear feet, 1957-2007) spans the entire history of the college and contains information from all the directors, different educational programs, and reviews of the Residential College. It also consists of reports to LSA on the RC, director and staff correspondence, committee (Curriculum Planning Committee, Educational Policies and Curriculum Committee, Liaison Committee, Residential College Advisory Committee) meetings minutes and reports, information on the 20th, 30th, and 40th anniversaries of the college, RC curriculum information and evaluations, and information on the Writers-In-Residence Group. Several of the Topical Files contain electronic mail (printed) from the RC Director Thomas Weisskopf and also include his own hand written notes about each topic. The series also contains posters and flyers on speakers participating in the Writers-In-Residence Group. Digital content (42 MB) includes word processing documents such as syllabi and course descriptions for the Russian program as well as an image of a poster for the 40th anniversary celebration.
  - Academic Services Report, 1987 (Box 20)
  - Administrative Curriculum Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 20)
  - Admissions, 1967-1974; 2003-2009; 8 folders (Box 20)
  - Admissions, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Aesthetics and Arts, 1964-1971 (Box 20)
  - Alumni, 1972-1977; 2001 (Box 20)
  - Anniversaries
    - 20th, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - 30th, 1997 (Box 20)
    - 40th, 2007 (Box 20)
    - 40th, 2007; .ZIP file
  - Annual Reports (First Annual Report -- Draft), 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - Announcement, 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - Appointments, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Architecture, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Art Gallery, 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Art Studio Design Sketches, undated (Folder 1)
  - Arts and Ideas Concentration in the Humanities, 1977-1996; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Arts and Ideas Concentration in the Humanities, 1980-1998; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Arts Program, 1996-2000 (Box 5)
  - Associate Director's Report, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - Awards Committee, 1997-2000 (Box 5)
  - Background Documents (Student Government), 1965-1967 (Box 5)
  - Bean, Henry, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Benzinger Library, 1957-2009 (Box 20)
  - Board on Academic Standing, 1967-1968 (Box 20)
  - Brecht Company, 1979-1989 (Box 20)
  - Budget Discussions, 2000-2002 (Box 5)
  - Business, 1980-1987 (Box 5)
  - Carl Cohen Correspondence, 1971-1999; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Carl Cohen Reading Room, 1998; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Charles Bright's Neuman File, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Christian, Bill, 2000 (Box 6)
  - COCOLARC (Community Initiative Program), 1996 (Box 6)
  - "Collegiate Federalism: The New Wave" (Box 6)
  - Community Forum, 1973-1974 (Box 20)
  - Community Government, 1968-1972 (Box 21)
  - Community Government Planning Documents, 1965-1968 (Box 6)
  - Community Initiative, 1996 (Box 21)
  - Community Initiative, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Comparative Literature, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Concentration/Program Descriptions, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Concentration "Programs,", 1969-1971 (Box 6)
  - Concentration Statistics, 1976-1993 (Box 21)
  - Constitution, 1970-1971; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Counseling, Admissions, and Recruitment, 1977-1981; undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Counseling Issues, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Course Approval Meetings, 1987-1989 (Box 6)
  - Course Descriptions and Schedules, 1985-1987 (Box 21)
  - Course Information, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - CORE (Courses) Curriculum, 1970-1973 (Box 21)
  - CORE (Courses) Curriculum, Winter, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Course Planning, 1997-1998 (Box 6)
  - Course Proposals, 1969-1974; undated; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Courses
    - Aids, 1992-1993 (Box 21)
    - Core 115-Alternate Realities, 1973 (Box 21)
    - Fundamentals of Prose Narrative, 1980 (Box 21)
    - History of Western Man, 1967-1969 (Box 21)
    - Human Behavior
      - Conflict in American History, 1972 (Box 21)
      - Networks, 1972 (Box 21)
      - Poverty, 1971 (Box 21)
      - Protest Movements, 1970 (Box 21)
      - Section A, 1968 (Box 21)
      - Section B, 1968; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Humanities
      - 214
        - Recent Prose: American Writing-Generations Lost and Beat, 1978 (Box 21)
        - Recent Prose: Cultural Values in Twentieth Century Fiction: Death Trip, 1977 (Box 21)
      - 251 and 252, 10 Year Report, 2000 (Box 21)
      - 255-The Film Experience, 1971 (Box 21)
      - 290-Arts and Ideas in the Twentieth Century: The Post-Modern Era, 1950-1970; 1978-1984; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Political Economy, 1973-1974 (Box 21)
    - Social Science
      - 290-Basic Seminar, 1985 (Box 21)
      - 360-Junior Seminar: Trends in American Health Care, 1982 (Box 21)
      - 385-Democracy in the Workplace, 1982-1983 (Box 21)
      - 460-Senior Seminar: Issues in Education, 1977 (Box 21)
  - Creative Writing, January 1979 (Box 6)
  - Curriculum, 1998-2000 (Box 6)
  - Curriculum Planning Committee, 2001-2002; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Curricular Reviews, 1970-1985 (Box 7)
  - Degree Requirements, 1973-1976 (Box 7)
  - Detroit Public Schools/University of Michigan Collaborative Project, 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Diploma, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Directorship, 1994-1999 (Box 7)
  - Diversity, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Diversity Seminars, 1998; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Drama Concentration Program, 1969-1979; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Dweck, Robbie, 1971 (Box 21)
    (Correspondence with Max Heirich and report on California-Berkeley)
  - East Quad Hymnals, 1970-1973 (Box 7)
  - East Quad Music Co-op, undated (Box 21)
  - Educational Policies Committee, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Educational Policies and Curriculum Committee
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming, 1971 (Box 7)
      - Outgoing, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - General (Box 22)
      - 1970s, 8 folders (Box 22)
      - 1980-1983 (Box 22)
      - 1986-1989 (Box 22)
      - 1989-1993, 2 folders (Box 22)
      - 1995-1999 (Box 7)
  - Endowments, 2000-2004 (Box 7)
  - Environmental Studies, 1999-2002 (Box 7)
  - Energy Conference-Energy for Michigan and the Great Lakes Region: a Briefing on the Nuclear Option (Box 23)
    - Backgrounders, 1975 (Box 23)
    - General, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Press Releases, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Energy Mini-Course-Energy for Michigan and the Great Lakes Region: a Briefing on the Nuclear Option, 1975 (Box 23)
  - Enrollment Reports, 1967-1995 (Box 23)
  - Evaluation Committee, 1970-1973 (Box 7)
  - Evaluations and Reviews, 1976-1979 (Box 7)
  - Events (Box 23)
    - 1968-1977, 1982-1987; 11 folders (Box 23)
    - 1999-2001 (Box 19)
      (includes RC Connection newsletters)
  - External Relations, 1999-2000; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - External Review-Language Programs, 1995-1997 (Box 23)
  - External Reviews, 1984-2004; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Fact Sheets, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Faculty Advisory Body, undated (Box 23)
  - Faculty Appointments and Institutional Review, 2001-2002; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Faculty Correspondence and Reports, 1972-2001; undated (Box 23)
  - Faculty Evaluation, 1988 (Box 31)
    [PR Restricted until July 1, 2018 ]
  - Faculty Evaluation, 2003-2004 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Meetings and Seminars, 2003 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Plans (Teaching), 1973-2002; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Faculty Policy, 1964-1974; 3 folders (Box 23)
  - Faculty Policy Guidelines, 1971-1979 (Box 23)
  - Faculty Recommendations, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Retreat, 1975 undated (Box 23)
  - Field Studies, 1976-1980; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Field Trip to Pioneer Valley, Massachusetts, 1983 (Box 23)
    (includes photographs)
  - Final Evaluation of Nurse Practitioners, Winter, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Frayn, Michael, 2000 (Box 8)
  - French Program, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Freshman Seminars (Box 23)
    - 1970-1989, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - 1990-2004 (Box 24)
  - Fundraising, 1966-1978 (Box 24)
  - Fundraising, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Future of RC Committee, 1996 (Box 8)
  - Gallery Show-"The Beer Lady Recovered,", 2005 (Box 24)
  - German Program, 1992-1999; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Goldenberg, Edie/Pat Gurin, 1997-1999 (Box 8)
  - Government: Women's Hours, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Grade Issues, 1999-2002; 6 folders (Box 8)
  - Graduation, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Graduation, 2003-2007 (Box 24)
  - Graduation/Attrition Rates, 1997-2001 (Box 24)
  - Group Dynamics, January-April 1977 (Box 8)
  - Guidelines and Proposals, 1968-1971 (Box 9)
  - Handbook for Counselors, 1967-1970; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Health Studies, 1996-1999 (Box 9)
  - Historical Documents, 1966-1987; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - History Critique, 1970-1974 (Box 9)
  - History of Residential College, 1976-1994 (Box 24)
  - Humanities Programs, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Independent Studies, 1973 undated (Box 24)
  - Independent Study Project-"The Sanctuary Movement-North American Congregations and Central American Refugees Building Friendships Across Borders,", 1986 (Box 24)
  - Individual Evaluations, Winter, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Information of the Residence College and University of Michigan (Students), 1967 (Box 9)
  - Informational, 1966-1977 (Box 19)
  - Interflex, 1972 (Box 24)
  - Internal Evaluations, February 3, 1977 (Box 9)
  - International Institute, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Japanese Dance Proposal, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Joint Board, 1971-1985; 4 folders (Box 24)
  - Joint Board, 1973-1983; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Joint Seminar Agendas, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Lacroute, Ronni, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Languages
    - 1994-1997 (Box 9)
    - 1997-2000 (Box 31)
      [SR Restricted until July 1, 2075 ]
  - Latin Program, 1999-2000 (Box 24)
  - Lecturers, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Liaison Committee, 1993-2000; 9 folders (Box 9)
  - Library Committee, 1972 (Box 24)
  - Library Program Study Report, September 1968 (Box 9)
  - Literature Concentration, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Literature Concentration, 1985 (Box 24)
  - Living-Learning, 1994 undated (Box 24)
  - Long Range Plan, 1967-2002; 9 folders (Box 9)
  - Long-Range Planning Group, 1985-1993 (Box 24)
  - LSA/RC Review, 1992-1993; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Mackenzie High School/Residential College Joint Projects, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Major Book, 1983-1984; undated (Box 10)
  - Mandate, undated (Box 24)
  - Materials for Charlie B. (Information on Directorship of RC for Charles Bright from Thomas Weisskopf), 2001 (Box 10)
  - Miles, Betty, 1983 (Box 10)
  - Minority Issues Committee, 1976 (Box 24)
  - Minors Exclusion, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, 1971-1985 (Box 10)
  - Michigan Learning Communities MLC, 1999M-Pathways RC/LSA Issues, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Music, 1972-1976 (Box 10)
  - Neuman, Shirley, 2001-2002 (Box 10)
  - News Clippings, 1962-1973; undated (Box 25)
  - Orientation, 1983-1989 (Box 25)
  - Shirley Neuman, Bob Owen, and Jim Adams, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Owen, Bob, 2003-2004 (Box 10)
  - Planning, 2002-2003 (Box 10)
  - RC Players, 1973-1976 (Box 10)
  - Practice/Clinical Professorship: Provost Rules, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Program Evaluation Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 25)
  - Program Proposals, 1970-1976; 1995-1997; undated (Box 25)
  - Publicity: Message of RC Recruitment, 2000-2001 (Box 10)
  - Quantitative Methods, 1995-1997 (Box 10)
  - Questionnaires, 1969-1985 (Box 10)
  - Reading Room, 1998-1999 (Box 25)
  - Renewal Committee, 1996 (Box 25)
  - Renovations, 1993 (Box 25)
  - Residential College Advisory Committee (RCAC) (Box 10)
    - Meetings
      - October 1995 (Box 10)
      - 1995 (Box 10)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 11)
      - 1997 (Box 11)
      - 1998 (Box 11)
      - 1999 (Box 11)
      - 2003 (Box 11)
  - Residential College New York City (RC NYC) Event, 1996 (Box 11)
  - Residential College 30th Anniversary Advisory Committee (RC 30 AC), 1997; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - RCAEP, 1996 (Box 11)
  - Recent RC Initiatives and Plans, 2001 (Box 11)
  - Residential College Social Science Program (RCSSP), 1997; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Reports
    - Collation, 1966-1987; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Theme Semester, 2002 (Box 11)
    - Evaluation Working Group, 1999 (Box 11)
    - Research Reports, 1968-1976 (Box 11)
    - RC Reports, 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Residential College Report, 1977-1981; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Resident Fellows Manuals, 1973-1976 (Box 12)
  - Residential Colleges in North America, 1977; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Rethinking Honors, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Reunion, 1980 (Box 25)
  - Review Committee, 1985 (Box 25)
  - Reviews (Box 12)
    - Critical Self-Examination of the Residential College for the Review Committee, November 1971 (Box 12)
    - RC Review, 1972-1977; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - RC Review Report, 1972 (Box 12)
    - Reviews of the Residential College, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
    - Review of Governance, Fall, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Russian Program
    - 1997 (Box 12)
    - 2002-2004, .ZIP file
      (Course descriptions and syllabi)
  - Science Program, 1995-1998 (Box 12)
  - RC Scrapbook, 1963-1967 (Box 12)
  - Residential College Self-Study Report, January 1998 (Box 12)
  - RC Self-Study Spanish Program, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Second Language Institution Report, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Senior Dinner, 1979-1989 (Box 25)
  - Shapiro, Harold T., 1971-1973 (Box 25)
  - Skills Workshop Agenda, Winter, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Social Science, 1997-2000 (Box 12)
  - Science, Technology, and Future Societies (STAFS) Seminar, 1973-1974 (Box 25)
  - Science, Technology, and Society (STS) Initiative, 1992-1997 (Box 25)
  - Science, Technology and Society (STS) Initiative, 2000 (Box 12)
  - Social Science Program PASTs, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Society for Religion in Higher Education, 1971 (Box 12)
  - South Dining, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Sowers, Cynthia-Correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 25)
    [PR Restricted until July 1, 2018; removed to box 31]
  - Space Committee, 1996-2000 (Box 25)
  - Spanish Program, 1983-1985 (Box 25)
  - Strategic Planning, 1998-2000; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Staff Correspondence, 1969-1975 (Box 13)
  - Student-Faculty Research Community in the Social Sciences: Research-based Teaching and Learning, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Student Assessment, 1972 (Box 25)
  - Student Data, 1995-1997 (Box 13)
  - Student Life, 1996-1998 (Box 13)
  - Supplement to the Handbook for Faculty Counselors, August 1975 (Box 13)
  - Survey of Freshman Admits (SOFA) Committee, 1993 (Box 25)
  - Term Enrollment Statistics and Projects, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Time Schedules/Course Descriptions, 1968-2001; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Triennial Reviews, 1981-1984 (Box 13)
  - Twentieth Anniversary, 1987 (Box 13)
  - Universities, Other, 1965-1977 (Box 25)
  - Website, 1997-2000 (Box 13)
  - Workshop, 1974 (Box 25)
  - Writers-In-Residence (Box 13)
    - 1972-1984, 9 folders (Box 13)
    - McMullen, Richard, April 1984 (Box 13)
    - Posters and Flyers, 1978-1984 (Box 13)
  - Wholistic Health Self-Evaluation, Winter, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Written Evaluations, 1999; 2 folders (Box 13)
- Audiovisual
  The Audiovisual series (59 GB, 1968-2007) includes a variety of different formats, including VHS tape, EIAJ-1 videotape, Mini DVs, audio cassettes, 7" and 10.5" reel-to-reel tape, 12" vinyl records, one 8mm film reel, and digital materials from CDs/DVDs. VHS tape content includes graduations from the early 1990s, events from the college's 30th anniversary celebration in 1997, a talk by James Robertson on the origins of the Residential College, symposia, interviews, and documentaries. While most of the EIAJ-1 videotapes are unlabeled, among them are a debate on nuclear power and inaugural festivities from 1973. The Mini DVs mostly contain faculty member interviews and video recordings of events such as the East Quad Music Festival and the RC Afro-Cuban Drumming Concert. Audio cassettes include faculty interviews and Student-Faculty Research Community research design training tapes. Reel-to-reel tapes contain recordings from music classes and concerts. The vinyl records contain recordings from the East Quad Music Co-op, including the album "All who Rob and Plunder" from the band Civilian Fun Group." Digital content (59 GB) includes video files of several student/alumni-produced films; course activities, including from a Nonviolence in Action course and an Afro-Cuban drumming course; recordings created for the college's website of faculty members and students discussing their experiences in the college; and two theatrical productions, "The Struggle for Existence: Darwin's Dreams" and "Blood Wedding."
  - VHS
    - 30th Anniversary Events, 1997; 12 tapes (Box 28)
    - Graduation, 1990-1993; 8 tapes (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-1994; undated; 24 tapes (Box 28)
  - EIAJ-1 Videotape, 1973-1976; undated; 13 reels (Box 29)
  - Mini DVs, 2006-2007; undated; 32 audiocassettes Mini DVs (Box 29)
  - Audio Cassettes
    - Miscellaneous, 2004-2005; undated; 17 tapes (Box 29)
    - Student-Faculty Research Community Research Design Training Tapes, 1979; 19 tapes (Box 29)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes
    - 7 inch, 1976-1978; 3 reels (Box 30)
    - 10.5 inch, 1968-1971; undated; 7 reels (Box 30)
  - 12 inch Phonograph Records, 2 12-inch Phonograph Records
    - 1985 (Sound-disc 1)
    - 1987 (Sound-disc 2)
  - Film-RC Flick, undated (Reel 1)
  - Digital Materials
    - Alumni/Student Works
      - Carbonell, Isabelle, circa 2000s; .ZIP and .MP4 files
      - Greene, David, 1971; .ZIP file
    - Courses, 2005-2006; .MP4 and .avi files
      (Includes materials from courses on "Nonviolence in Action" and Afro-Cuban drumming.)
    - Introductions to Residential College
      - Bright, Charles, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Eagle, Herb, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Genne, Beth, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Gould, Michael, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Mendeloff, Kate, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Murphy, Charles, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Regester, Craig, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Rodriguez, Mabel, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Students, 2007; .ZIP file
      - Weisskopf, Thomas, 2007; .ZIP file
    - Self-Portraits of the Residential College, circa 2007; .MP4 files
    - Theatrical Productions
      - "Blood Wedding", 2006; .MP4 and .ZIP file
      - "The Struggle for Existence: Darwin's Dreams", 2006; .MP4 and .ZIP file
- Archived Website
  The Archived Website series (205 MB, 1998-) includes captures of the Residential College website and documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the Residential College. Content includes information for prospective students explaining what RC is and what it offers as well as information for current RC community members such as faculty and staff listings, list of events, newsletters, program and course guides, graduation requirements, and student activities descriptions. The series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 1998 as well as versions from 2001, 2003, and 2007 originally stored on optical discs. The 2003 capture is from "The Art (and politics) of War" pilot sub-section of the RC website. Since 2010, this archived website has been captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - 1998-2011
    (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
  - 2001, .ZIP file
  - 2003, .ZIP file
  - 2007, .ZIP file
  - 2010-[ONGOING]